Kia Rahmani, Ph.D.

└ 765-588-8872 **○** kiarahmani

✓ kiar@utexas.edu

Austin, TX kiarahmani.github.io in kia-rahmani

I am a computer scientist with over 10 years of research experience in the industry and academia. I am passionate about designing programming language-based tools to enable more generalizable, interpretable, and reliable machine/robot learning algorithms. I am a highly motivated team player and am always eager to learn new things.

Education

Purdue University 2017 - 2022

Ph.D. in Computer Science

IN, USA

- > Thesis: Symbolic Analysis of Weak Concurrency Semantics in Modern Database Programs
- > Advisors: Suresh Jagannathan & Benjamin Delaware

Purdue University 2015 - 2017

M.Sc. in Computer Science

IN, USA

> Selected Courses: Programming Languages, Adv. Topics in Programming Languages, Computer-aided Reasoning, Distributed Database Systems, Verifying Systems At Scale, Formal Methods In Databases, Information Security

Sharif University of Technology

2010 - 2015

B.Sc. in Computer Science

Tehran, IRAN

> Undergraduate Thesis: A Survey on Three-ballot Voting Mechanism: Algorithms and Attacks

Work Experience

The University of Texas at Austin Post-doctoral Scientist

09/2022 - Current

TX, USA

- > Research Focus: Symbolic Methods for Robot Learning from Demonstration and Experience
- > Advisors: Isil Dillig & Joydeep Biswas

Microsoft Corporation

06/2020 - 12/2020

Research Intern

WA, USA

- > Project: Program Inference using Large Language Models
- > Supervisors: Sumit Gulwani & Mohammad Raza

Graduate Research and Teaching Assistant

Purdue University

08/2015 - 08/2022

IN, USA

Publications & Patents

Programmatic Imitation Learning from Unlabeled and Noisy Demonstrations (arxiv)

Under Submission

> Jimmy Xin, Linus Zheng, Jiayi Wei, Kia Rahmani, Jarrett Holtz, Isil Dillig, Joydeep Biswas

Programming-by-Demonstration for Long-Horizon Robot Tasks (arxiv)

POPL'24

> Noah Patton, Kia Rahmani, Meghana Missula, Joydeep Biswas, Isil Dillig

Multi-modal Program Inference (USPTO Application)

US 20230176829A1

> Kia Rahmani, Mohammad Raza, Sumit Gulwani, Vu Le, Daniel Morris, Arjun Radhakrishna, Gustavo Soares, Ashish Tiwari

Multi-modal Program Inference: LLMs and Component-based Synthesis (doi)

OOPSLA'21

> Kia Rahmani, Mohammad Raza, Sumit Gulwani, Vu Le, Daniel Morris, Arjun Radhakrishna, Gustavo Soares, Ashish Tiwari

Repairing Serializability Bugs in Distributed Database Programs via Automated Schema Refactoring (doi)

PLDI'21

> Kia Rahmani, Kartik Nagar, Benjamin Delaware and Suresh Jagannathan

CLOTHO: Directed Test Generation for Weakly Consistent Database Systems (doi)

OOPSLA'19

> Kia Rahmani, Kartik Nagar, Benjamin Delaware and Suresh Jagannathan

Fine-grained Distributed Consistency Guarantees with Effect Orchestration (doi)

PaPoC'18

> Kia Rahmani, Gowtham Kaki and Suresh Jagannathan

Kia Rahmani, Ph.D.

Post-doctoral Scientist

└ 765-588-8872 **○** kiarahmani Austin, TX

kiarahmani.github.io in kia-rahmani

✓ kiar@utexas.edu

♥ Skills

Programming Languages I have worked on numerous projects written in various programming languages, and I am proficient in C/C++, Java, C#, Python, Haskell, OCaml, etc.

Formal Methods I have a deep knowledge of logical frameworks for specifying computer systems and their properties, which I have utilized in my past research, including temporal logics (such as LTL, CTL, STL, etc.), rely-guarantee reasoning (RG), separation logic (SL), correctness/incorrectness logic, etc.

Model Checking and Verification I have acquired extensive experience in reducing a wide range of program analysis and verification problems to SAT and SMT instances. I am proficient in utilizing several prominent tools in this domain, such as Z3, Spin, Dafny, Alloy, Ultimate, SeaHorn, CVC-5, and Coq.

Databases and Data Management I have an extensive background in analyzing and implementing distributed data management systems with a wide range of concurrency semantics. I have developed multiple software applications that utilize various off-the-shelf database systems, including MongoDB, Apache Cassandra, Spanner, CosmosDB, PostgreSQL, MySQL, and more. I have also used several libraries for MVC design, including Django, Ruby on Rails, and Spring.

Machine Learning I have knowledge of various deep learning algorithms, with a particular focus on higher-level frameworks such as imitation learning, behavior cloning, and reinforcement learning. I am familiar with existing libraries such as PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, OpenAI Gym, and Stable-Baselines3.

DevOps Tool I am familiar with many software engineering and infrastructure automation tools, including Git, Docker, Kubernetes, Ansible, Jira, Unix system programming and AWS cloud programming.

■ Mentorship

Noah Patton CS Ph.D. Student , The University of Texas at Austin

Meghana Missula CS M.Sc. Student, The University of Texas at Austin → Quantitative Strategist Intern @Goldman Sachs

Aneesh Shetty CS M.Sc. Student , The University of Texas at Austin \rightarrow SDE Intern @Amazon

Justus Fasse CS Ph.D. Student, KU Leuven through Sigplan-M long-term Mentorship Program

Jimmy Xin Turing Undergraduate Scholar, The University of Texas at Austin → Software Development Intern DLZP Group

≡ References

Isil Dillig Professor, The University of Texas at Austin, isil@cs.utexas.edu

Suresh Jagannthan Samuel D. Conte Professor, Purdue University, suresh@cs.purdue.edu

Sumit Gulwani Partner Research Manager, Microsoft Corporation, sumitg@microsoft.com

Benjamin Delaware Assistant Professor, Purdue University, bendy@purdue.edu

Joydeep Biswas Associate Professor, The University of Texas at Austin, joydeepb@cs.utexas.edu